[Music]
thanks for tuning in to this earnings
conversation
despite I lost in the equity investments
driven by improvement in loss ratio as
well as market share gains ICICI Lombard
reported an inline quarter for let's
talk about the highlights of the quarter
but more importantly what could the
near-term near future hold in store mr.
Park of Dasgupta Indians MD and CEO of
the company John Astra John says right
now on this conversation is booked up
mr. Gupta thanks so much for taking the
time out and speaking to us at Bluebird
Quinn needed here thank you for having
me Malaysia can you sum up the quarter I
mean we had about seven days of a
lockdown what kind of an impact that it
had on the for business
never mind the equity valuation losses
that you would have had yeah so I mean
obviously the you know market meltdown
that we saw if you look at our
investment portfolio we have a large
exposure in the debt side but equally we
have about ten eleven percent of our
exposure on the equity side on the
inquiry' side we had a sharp you know
correction and prices and in fact our
market position ended with about - I 50
crores out of which we have our
impairment policy we look at stock
specific video stock specific analysis
and we look at whether we need to add
you know diminution in the P&L so we
took a 120 crore hit in the PNL last
quarter but you know in terms of the
outlook we believe these are good
quality investments that we have and in
the long term we should see the value
come back but a larger question that you
asked was in terms of business you if
you see for the whole year we grew you
know at about shade more than 10 percent
about 10.5% but for the quarter we grew
at only about two and a half percent
about 2.9 percent this is excluding the
crop segment which is a segment that we
didn't get any business last year so
there was a huge impact into the
business
we are seeing it even now as we go
through this month of April in me so I
just put this into perspective and then
I'll come to individual segments as well
mr. Dasgupta we had a we had a seven day
of a lockdown and I was speaking to one
of your peers in the life insurance
space who told me back then that the
busines had come to a grinding halt I'm
guessing for general insurance it's
probably not as much because some of
these things happen on autopilot and
auto-renewal
so on so forth what is the experience
been of the last seven days of March and
therefore if that is any benchmark would
you praise me June show significant
impact of that so the impact you just
felt you know segment by segment
differently so if you look at for the
general insurance industry the point is
valid that there is a renewal that comes
because we don't write long term
policies largely the right-hand-rule
policies and policies get renewed but if
you look at different segments of
business the largest segment of business
for the general insurance industry is is
auto insurance and if you look at the
auto insurance sector new vehicle sales
as you've seen most of items reporter is
down to zero in the month of April so
new insurance policy shields have
basically gone down to nothing what
we're seeing is renewals in the motor
segment and that number is also a bit
muted compared to what we normally see
in the renewal rates at least for us I
can speak for ourselves our cents
talking to our distributors talking our
customers there may be some amount of
postponement of renewals that is
happening and once things normalize and
lockdown eases people will come back and
renew their policies so that's number
one on the health side we are either
there are two extra key segments one is
the corporate segment where corporates
buy health insurance for their employees
and that segment has been largely
predicted so people are obviously buying
in health insurance and that's the in
fact you know the demand for that could
actually increase as we go along the
second is a retail segment and the
retail segment there are two types of
policies that we sell
one is indemnity policy which is you
know the typical Medicare policies where
we pay for hospitalization when you you
know all the cost of hospitalization
that's one type of policy the other type
of policy is critical illness disease
specific benefit policies which largely
get sold through distribution partners
banks you know as attachments so the
second category has dropped because the
disbursements have known etcetera have
also dropped but on the indemnity side
the demand is you know reasonably stable
people are renewing obviously the
concern at this point and people are
renewing and the the inquiries of
increase what is not happening is the
rate of conversion of these inquiries
have dropped again probably because
people want to do it but maybe you know
delaying the decision so those are the
two one segment of the details yet good
two key segments on the retail side on
the b2b side that is corporates who buy
insurance for you know fire damage
you know projects insurance marine all
of that is as of now largely protected
but we are seeing some stress in the
corporate sector in terms of working
capital stress and you know there are
some requests for installments there are
some proposals for reducing the coverage
but as of now the b2b segment is still
fine okay so I have two questions one is
on the slightly long term but one is the
immediate term speaking of policy
bizarre and they mentioned that some of
their customers are allowing the motor
insurance to lapse for a bit because
they are not going to take out their
cars for the foreseeable future or
two-wheelers and therefore once they do
that they will come they will come back
so my question is even if this auto
insurance as you said for you who has
been a bit muted to do you reckon it's
not demand for gone but demand postponed
and therefore we come back if not in May
then in June if not if June than in July
yeah the money will come back as I said
you know people a certain percentage of
people are postponing the renewals for
the same reason that you articulated but
obviously you need insurance to drive
your vehicle so the demand will come
back okay the other bit is servant wear
life insurance companies at least say
that this might actually have a bit of a
long-term positive impact on insurance
just simply because
people will be aware that they need to
ensure everything under the Sun right
now because this makes people aware of
how how we you know the mortality can be
anytime
so would you reckon that the quantum of
insurance that people take not just in
life but in general insurance as well
could actually move up in some fashion
health insurance for example could that
all move up yeah so if you see you know
examples in the past if you see what
happened post SARS in Hong Kong or even
if you what you're seeing in China right
now where things seems to be stabilizing
a lot more we've seen significant
increase in health insurance interest in
health insurer the health insurance
premium and you know what you're you
know the my colleagues or the life
insurance industry would have told you
is true for any type of protection when
events like this happen
I think the realization that you need to
protect yourself or protect your assets
increases and that's why the protection
increases for some time so in the
long-term we believe I mean look at the
end of the day this is not a time when
we talk about what we gain from it I
it's an unfortunate development but
having said that in the long term
this definitely will have positive
impact in terms of demand for any type
of reduction mr. Gupta I won't take too
much of your time but just one question
because a lot of the things are moving
an important table so I won't dwell too
much on the near tomorrow ease and the
growth etcetera a lot of people are
penciling in various kinds of growth
estimates I won't get into that because
I'm guessing it's difficult to pencil in
one one thing would you reckon that or
any player and including you is amongst
the largest players in the country
growth in f1 21 would be a large factor
of how quickly the auto space bounces
back and if it doesn't is is growth
under cloud so too has tremendous impact
on the overall economy writing this is a
number of linked industries that is
suppose the jobs that it supports the
number of dealerships and the employee
base in the dealerships
you know we keep talking to our channel
partners our dealer partners etc and
then there is tremendous stress
in terms of predicting what will happen
honestly as you rightly said it's you
know it needs a brave heart to predict
anything at this point in time because
you don't know how this you know pirates
will will pan out and when we will see
some of the orange zones become green
zones when the red zones will become in
orange tones it's almost impossible to
predict as we see it here and the second
important herbal is the fiscal support
that is provided to the to the auto
sector you know one of the things that I
would definitely the government to
consider would be a vehicle scrappage
policy whenever they are able to come
out with the package you know clunker
kind of a scheme for maybe a six month
period would go a long way in helping
the auto industry and if the auto
industry itself I think the overall
economy also benefit I'm completely
aware of the concerns and the constraint
that we have in terms of our fiscal
space but that would be an important you
know important support for the benefit
of the larger ecosystem so if all of
these things happen the numbers can you
know come up in the second half there is
also a debate that or a thought that
given the concern about using public
transport people may want to you know
increase the a choice in terms of
personal mobility and that could
increase demand for the lower end of the
vehicles maybe two wheelers or low rent
cars so these are all possibilities it's
very difficult to predict what will
actually happen and how customers will
behave when things normalized mr.
Dasgupta appreciate you taking the time
out and being so candid and I wish you
all the best for the time Syed please
stay safe thank you too much favorite
right and that's I say say Lombard on
how the quarter went by difficult to
give estimates or half the year would be
but I think she tried his best to give
us as Canada picture as possible viewers
thanks for tuning in this broadcast
[Music]
you